<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on My Bare Metal Life</title>
    <link>http://blog.abnormal-intelligence.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on My Bare Metal Life</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 12:27:48 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.abnormal-intelligence.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why Bare Metal</title>
      <link>http://blog.abnormal-intelligence.com/posts/why-bare-metal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 12:27:48 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.abnormal-intelligence.com/posts/why-bare-metal/</guid>
      <description>Popular Capitalism Popular Capitalism was all the rage in 1982. The markets were being freed from the deadening hand of oppressive market regulations. The most vibrant sector of the new market economy was the consumer tech sector, especially affordable home computers. The two leading tech entrepreneurs in the UK at the time were Sir Clive Sinclar and Alan Sugar of Amstrad. These guys were my teenage heros.
Mr Shawcross My mother was a founder member of the Over-25 Club, a social group for people who wanted to go on rambles, play boardgames, etc, with like-minded people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Language Learning</title>
      <link>http://blog.abnormal-intelligence.com/posts/language-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 08:40:56 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.abnormal-intelligence.com/posts/language-learning/</guid>
      <description>Mr Knight When I started High School, it was the first time that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sent off to school in a butyric-acid-generating Thrift Shop uniform. Things were definitely improving for us under Maggie Fatcher.
The French teacher, Mr Knight, was a man in his fifties who was going to seed. He teeth were beyond what Americans think of as British Teeth. He smelled of garlic. He was a chain smoker and his tweed jacket reeked of tobacco and nicotine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bare Metal Blog</title>
      <link>http://blog.abnormal-intelligence.com/posts/bare-metal-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 05:41:15 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.abnormal-intelligence.com/posts/bare-metal-blog/</guid>
      <description>This is just a blog My life Stories from my past Some of my thoughts No affiliate links No comments section No spammy email signup thing. If you want to know when I post something new, I will announce it in this Telegram group and this Signal group</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anna Karenina</title>
      <link>http://blog.abnormal-intelligence.com/posts/anna-karenina/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 08:05:33 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.abnormal-intelligence.com/posts/anna-karenina/</guid>
      <description>The book on my mother&amp;rsquo;s bedside table I first encountered Anna when I was 17. I saw the book on my mother&amp;rsquo;s bedside table. The title immediately attracted me. Anna Karenina. The name sounded beautiful, Russian and mysterious. I started reading:
Happy families are all alike; every unhappy family is unhappy in its own way.
If I&amp;rsquo;m not hooked by the first line of a book, it&amp;rsquo;s usually a sign I will struggle with the rest of the book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bare Metal Horticulture</title>
      <link>http://blog.abnormal-intelligence.com/posts/bare-metal-horticulture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 20:38:25 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.abnormal-intelligence.com/posts/bare-metal-horticulture/</guid>
      <description>Maggie Fatcher When I was 9, Mr Woolgar, the odd job man who did odd jobs for us, let me stay with him and his family at Butlins in Bognor Regis. I didn&amp;rsquo;t know why I was sent there but it was fun playing in the boats and the monorail. Mr Woolgar put the telly on in the evening for the news about the 1979 General Election. Maggie Fatcher had won.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bare Metal Childhood</title>
      <link>http://blog.abnormal-intelligence.com/posts/bare-metal-childhood/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 19:51:55 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.abnormal-intelligence.com/posts/bare-metal-childhood/</guid>
      <description>Cartage Sussex is famous now because of its troublesome Duchess but the county she is Duchess of is an ancient Saxon kingdom that stubbornly maintained its independence for centuries before falling to the sword of Wessex, and eventually becoming a very English part of England.
The Isle of Wight, too, was a fiercely independent appendage at the bottom of England that bore the brunt of many French adventures over the centuries.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
